# **Guillermo Camargo**

Cra. 42E # 90 - 101. Barranquilla, Colombia / (+57) 3205812384 / gjcamargo@uninorte.edu.co/

Mechanical Engineer with an educational background in maintenance, thermodynamic processes, mechanical design and research. Experience encompasses maintenance scheduling of trucks in an open-pit coal mine and human resources. Strong ability to lead and work in teams, highly motivated and responsible.

## **KEY STRENGHTS**

- Leadership
- •Team Work
- Planning
- Adaptability
- Problem Solving
- Strong Work Ethic
- Creativity
- Motivation
- Multitasking
- Prioritizing

#### SOFTWARE SKILLS

- Office (Word, Excel, Access, Power Point, etc.)
- Matlab
- Solidworks
- AutoCad
- Aspen One (Hysys, Plus, etc.)
- Nessus
- Statsgraphics
- Expert Choice
- PeopleSoft

#### LANGUAGES

- English (Advanced TOFEL iBT)
- French (Intermediate DELF B1)
- German (Beginner)
- Spanish (Native)

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## MAINTENANCE SCHEDULER at DRUMMOND LTD.

La Loma, Cesar. Colombia • Sept 2017 to Mar 2018.

- + Make follow-ups to the trucks of the 777 fleet.
- + Update the daily hourmeter of the equipment.
- + Schedule the trucks to Preventive Maintenance (PM).
- + Create, relate and/or close work orders.
- + Evaluate the weekly Service Accuracy of the PMs scheduled.
- + Register the tracking of the removed and installed components in the trucks.

As a highlight during this experience, I contributed to the evaluation of the performance of the Single Point Lubricators installed on the fleet's trucks, as well as, the technical skills of the technicians in its maintenance, proposing improvements and suggestions to its maintenance guidelines.

#### MATCH IGIP COORDINATOR at AIESEC Uninorte.

Barranquilla, Atlántico. Colombia • Jan 2014 to Jun 2014.

Supervise and delegate work along the Match team, as well as:

- + Establish work alliances with other local committees around the world.
- + Coordinate job selection process with companies.

## TEAM MEMBER MATCH IGIP at AIESEC Uninorte.

Barranguilla, Atlántico. Colombia • Jul 2013 to Dic 2013.

- + Search and interview job applicants
- + Guide applicants through visa application process and arrival to Colombia.

## **EDUCATION**

- **+BACHELOR DEGREE IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING** from Universidad del Norte. Barranquilla, Colombia (2013-2018).
- **+MECHANICAL ENGINEERING-EXCHANGE PROGRAM** from Texas Tech University. Lubbock, TX, United States (2017-2017).
- **+HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA** from Colegio Biffi La Salle. Barranquilla, Colombia (2012).